{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Entrepreneur",
    "Term": "First Quarter",
    "Title": "Week-1",
    "LastModified": "14 August 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "Week-1"
    ]
  },
"quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What is the relevance of entrepreneurship where one of the benefits an entrepreneur gets is to develop his managerial skills?",
      "answer": "Development of Managerial Capabilities",
      "choices": [
        "Creation of Organizations",
        "Improving Standard of Living",
        "Means of Economic Development",
        "Development of Managerial Capabilities"
      ],
      "reference": "Relevance of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the relevance of entrepreneurship which means that because of it many organizations will exist?",
      "answer": "Creation of Organizations",
      "choices": [
        "Development of Managerial Capabilities",
        "Improving Standard of Living",
        "Means of Economic Development",
        "Creation of Organizations"
      ],
      "reference": "Relevance of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the relevance of entrepreneurship that can lift up the economic status of an individual?",
      "answer": "Improving Standard of Living",
      "choices": [
        "Development of Managerial Capabilities",
        "Creation of Organizations",
        "Means of Economic Development",
        "Improving Standard of Living"
      ],
      "reference": "Relevance of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the relevance of entrepreneurship where not only the life of the entrepreneur is improved but also the society where the business is located?",
      "answer": "Means of Economic Development",
      "choices": [
        "Development of Managerial Capabilities",
        "Creation of Organizations",
        "Improving Standard of Living",
        "Means of Economic Development"
      ],
      "reference": "Relevance of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What was derived from the French verb entreprendre, which means “to undertake?”",
      "answer": "Entrepreneur",
      "choices": [
        "Entrepreneurship",
        "Enterprise",
        "Innovators",
        "Entrepreneur"
      ],
      "reference": "Concept of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the process called when an enterprise is created by an entrepreneur?",
      "answer": "Entrepreneurship",
      "choices": [
        "Entrepreneur",
        "Enterprise",
        "Innovators",
        "Entrepreneurship"
      ],
      "reference": "Concept of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who are innovators?",
      "answer": "Entrepreneurs",
      "choices": [
        "Business Consultant",
        "Teacher",
        "Researcher",
        "Entrepreneurs"
      ],
      "reference": "Concept of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who are willing to take the risks and generate unique ideas that can provide profitable solutions to the needs of the market and the society?",
      "answer": "Entrepreneurs",
      "choices": [
        "Business Consultant",
        "Teacher",
        "Researcher",
        "Entrepreneurs"
      ],
      "reference": "Concept of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What personality factor is doing things even before being told?",
      "answer": "Initiative",
      "choices": [
        "Proactive",
        "Problem Solver",
        "Perseverance",
        "Initiative"
      ],
      "reference": "Factors Affecting Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What personality factor means he can classify opportunities and seize it?",
      "answer": "Proactive",
      "choices": [
        "Initiative",
        "Problem Solver",
        "Perseverance",
        "Proactive"
      ],
      "reference": "Factors Affecting Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What personality factor means he can retain good relations with other people?",
      "answer": "Problem Solver",
      "choices": [
        "Initiative",
        "Proactive",
        "Perseverance",
        "Problem Solver"
      ],
      "reference": "Factors Affecting Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What personality factor means he will pursue things to get done regardless of challenges?",
      "answer": "Perseverance",
      "choices": [
        "Initiative",
        "Proactive",
        "Problem Solver",
        "Perseverance"
      ],
      "reference": "Factors Affecting Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What personality factor means that he can entice people to buy even if they don’t want to?",
      "answer": "Persuasion",
      "choices": [
        "A Planner",
        "Risk-taker",
        "Proactive",
        "Persuasion"
      ],
      "reference": "Factors Affecting Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What personality factor means he makes plans before doing things and does not fail to monitor it?",
      "answer": "A Planner",
      "choices": [
        "Persuasion",
        "Risk-taker",
        "Proactive",
        "A Planner"
      ],
      "reference": "Factors Affecting Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What personality factor means that he is willing to gamble but he will calculate it first?",
      "answer": "Risk-taker",
      "choices": [
        "Persuasion",
        "A Planner",
        "Proactive",
        "Risk-taker"
      ],
      "reference": "Factors Affecting Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What factors include political, climate, legal system, economic and social conditions and market situations?",
      "answer": "Environmental Factors",
      "choices": [
        "Personality Factors",
        "Core Competencies",
        "Common Competencies",
        "Environmental Factors"
      ],
      "reference": "Factors Affecting Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What common competency means an entrepreneur must be firm in making decisions?",
      "answer": "Decisive",
      "choices": [
        "Communicator",
        "Leader",
        "Opportunity seeker",
        "Decisive"
      ],
      "reference": "Common Competencies in Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What common competency means an entrepreneur must have a convincing power?",
      "answer": "Communicator",
      "choices": [
        "Decisive",
        "Leader",
        "Opportunity seeker",
        "Communicator"
      ],
      "reference": "Common Competencies in Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What common competency means an entrepreneur must have the charisma to be obeyed by his employees?",
      "answer": "Leader",
      "choices": [
        "Decisive",
        "Communicator",
        "Opportunity seeker",
        "Leader"
      ],
      "reference": "Common Competencies in Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What common competency means an entrepreneur must have the ability to be the first to see business chances?",
      "answer": "Opportunity seeker",
      "choices": [
        "Decisive",
        "Communicator",
        "Leader",
        "Opportunity seeker"
      ],
      "reference": "Common Competencies in Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What common competency means an entrepreneur can control a situation by making things happen or by preparing for possible future problems?",
      "answer": "Proactive",
      "choices": [
        "Risk Taker",
        "Innovative",
        "Leader",
        "Proactive"
      ],
      "reference": "Common Competencies in Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What common competency means an entrepreneur has the courage to pursue business ideas?",
      "answer": "Risk Taker",
      "choices": [
        "Proactive",
        "Innovative",
        "Leader",
        "Risk Taker"
      ],
      "reference": "Common Competencies in Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What common competency means the entrepreneur has big business ideas and he does not stop improving and thinking of new worthwhile ideas for his business?",
      "answer": "Innovative",
      "choices": [
        "Proactive",
        "Risk Taker",
        "Leader",
        "Innovative"
      ],
      "reference": "Common Competencies in Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What core competency is an economic activity because it involves the creation and operation of an enterprise with a view to creating value or wealth by ensuring optimum utilization of limited resources?",
      "answer": "Economic and Dynamic Activity",
      "choices": [
        "Innovative",
        "Profit Potential",
        "Risk bearing",
        "Economic and Dynamic Activity"
      ],
      "reference": "Core Competencies in Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What core competency means the entrepreneur constantly looks for new ideas, thus he needs to be creative?",
      "answer": "Innovative",
      "choices": [
        "Economic and Dynamic Activity",
        "Profit Potential",
        "Risk bearing",
        "Innovative"
      ],
      "reference": "Core Competencies in Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What core competency means the entrepreneur can be compensated by his profit coming from the operation?",
      "answer": "Profit Potential",
      "choices": [
        "Economic and Dynamic Activity",
        "Innovative",
        "Risk bearing",
        "Profit Potential"
      ],
      "reference": "Core Competencies in Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What core competency means the entrepreneur needs to gamble but wise enough to offset the risk?",
      "answer": "Risk bearing",
      "choices": [
        "Economic and Dynamic Activity",
        "Innovative",
        "Profit Potential",
        "Risk bearing"
      ],
      "reference": "Core Competencies in Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of entrepreneurs are those who always make new things by thinking of new ideas?",
      "answer": "Innovative Entrepreneurs",
      "choices": [
        "Imitating Entrepreneurs",
        "Fabian Entrepreneurs",
        "Drone Entrepreneurs",
        "Innovative Entrepreneurs"
      ],
      "reference": "Types of Entrepreneurs",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of entrepreneurs have the ability to think newer, better and more economical ideas?",
      "answer": "Innovative Entrepreneurs",
      "choices": [
        "Imitating Entrepreneurs",
        "Fabian Entrepreneurs",
        "Drone Entrepreneurs",
        "Innovative Entrepreneurs"
      ],
      "reference": "Types of Entrepreneurs",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of entrepreneurs are those who don’t create new things but only follow the ideas of other entrepreneurs?",
      "answer": "Imitating Entrepreneurs",
      "choices": [
        "Innovative Entrepreneurs",
        "Fabian Entrepreneurs",
        "Drone Entrepreneurs",
        "Imitating Entrepreneurs"
      ],
      "reference": "Types of Entrepreneurs",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of entrepreneurs are skeptical about changes to be made in the organization?",
      "answer": "Fabian Entrepreneurs",
      "choices": [
        "Innovative Entrepreneurs",
        "Imitating Entrepreneurs",
        "Drone Entrepreneurs",
        "Fabian Entrepreneurs"
      ],
      "reference": "Types of Entrepreneurs",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of entrepreneurs don’t initiate but follow only after they are satisfied?",
      "answer": "Fabian Entrepreneurs",
      "choices": [
        "Innovative Entrepreneurs",
        "Imitating Entrepreneurs",
        "Drone Entrepreneurs",
        "Fabian Entrepreneurs"
      ],
      "reference": "Types of Entrepreneurs",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of entrepreneurs are those who live on the labor of others?",
      "answer": "Drone Entrepreneurs",
      "choices": [
        "Innovative Entrepreneurs",
        "Imitating Entrepreneurs",
        "Fabian Entrepreneurs",
        "Drone Entrepreneurs"
      ],
      "reference": "Types of Entrepreneurs",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of entrepreneurs are die-hard conservatives even ready to suffer the loss of business?",
      "answer": "Drone Entrepreneurs",
      "choices": [
        "Innovative Entrepreneurs",
        "Imitating Entrepreneurs",
        "Fabian Entrepreneurs",
        "Drone Entrepreneurs"
      ],
      "reference": "Types of Entrepreneurs",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of entrepreneurs are those who initiate changes and drive social innovation and transformation in the various fields such as education, health, human rights, environment and enterprise development?",
      "answer": "Social Entrepreneurs",
      "choices": [
        "Innovative Entrepreneurs",
        "Imitating Entrepreneurs",
        "Drone Entrepreneurs",
        "Social Entrepreneurs"
      ],
      "reference": "Types of Entrepreneurs",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What career opportunity means that with the expertise of in the field of entrepreneurship, he can be a very good source of advices to other entrepreneurs and would be businessmen?",
      "answer": "Business Consultant",
      "choices": [
        "Teacher",
        "Researcher",
        "Sales",
        "Business Consultant"
      ],
      "reference": "Career Opportunities of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What career opportunity means a graduate of an entrepreneurship can use his knowledge in teaching?",
      "answer": "Teacher",
      "choices": [
        "Business Consultant",
        "Researcher",
        "Sales",
        "Teacher"
      ],
      "reference": "Career Opportunities of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What career opportunity means the entrepreneur can be employed as a researcher by an enterprise?",
      "answer": "Researcher",
      "choices": [
        "Business Consultant",
        "Teacher",
        "Sales",
        "Researcher"
      ],
      "reference": "Career Opportunities of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What career opportunity means the entrepreneurship graduate can apply as a salesman?",
      "answer": "Sales",
      "choices": [
        "Business Consultant",
        "Teacher",
        "Researcher",
        "Sales"
      ],
      "reference": "Career Opportunities of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What career opportunity means the entrepreneur being expert in the field, can be employed as a business reporter?",
      "answer": "Business Reporter",
      "choices": [
        "Business Consultant",
        "Teacher",
        "Researcher",
        "Business Reporter"
      ],
      "reference": "Career Opportunities of Entrepreneurship",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    }
  ]
}